Guide to the Woman's College records, 1928-1974 UA.25.05.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Office of the Dean.1928-1974
  - Alphabetical Subject Files, 1928-1974 [Dc60s; MGW38-70; OD25-70; OD25-72; OD30-71; OD43-63; OD45-72; OD45-72; OD62-72; OD63-71; ODc60s; ODMF63-73; ODMGW33-69]., 24 boxes
    - WDBS, Student Radio Station, n.d., 1951 (Box 44)
    - WSGA, Woman's Student Government Association, General, 1935-1968 (Box 44)
    - WSGA, Assembly Agendas, 1954-1961 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Banquet, 1965-1966 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Budget, 1950; 1950; 1963-1966 (Box 45)
    - [WSGA], Car Issue, 1964-1968 (see also Automobiles, above) (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Cabinet, 1968-1969 [FERPA] (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Constitution, 1963-1967 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Coordinate Board, n.d; 1957-1965 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Correspondence, 1939-1945 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Evaluation Committee Report, 1960 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Faculty Relations Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Handbook, 1961-1969 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Lansing Campus Letter, 1954-1959 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Legislature Meeting, minutes, 1961-1969 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Newsletter, 1959-1967 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Officers and Elections, 1948-1970 (Box 45)
    - [WSGA], Orientation Week, 1963 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Questionnaire, 1965-1966 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Philosophy Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, President's Annual Report, 1948-1961 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Reports, Presidents and Judicial Board Chairman, 1961-1966 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Resolutions, 1962-1968 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Staff Recommendations and Approvals, 1931-1955 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, State Student Legislature, 1954-1970 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Student Welfare Committee, 1964-1966 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Study and Reevaluation of Class Structure, 1966-1967 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Treasurer's Report, annual, 1949; 1955-1959 (Box 45)
    - WSGA, Tutorial System, n.d. (Box 45)
    - Wilson, Mary Grace, Dean of Women, 1964-1972 (Box 45)
    - Wannamaker, W.H., Correspondence, 1930-1947 (Box 45)
    - War Activities of the Woman's College, 1941-1942 (Box 45)
    - Webb Collection Inventory, 1966 (Box 45)
    - White Duchy, 1951-1968 (Box 45)
    - Who's Who Among Students, 1958-1972 (Box 45)
    - Who's Who in American Colleges and Universities, 1953-1963 (Box 45)
    - Withdrawals, 1964-1967 (Box 45)
    - Woman's College History, 1928-1973, (contains a handwritten note from the Giles sisters) (Box 46)
    - Woman's College, Report to Dr. Hopkins, 1963-1965 (Box 46)
    - Woman's College, Report to President Knight, Program of the Woman's College, 1963-1964 (Box 46)
    - Woman's Liberation, 1968 (Box 46)
    - Women at Duke, 1930-1979 (Box 46)
    - "Women's Education in the 1970's," [session of the Board of Visitors], 1966; 1971 (Box 46)
    - Women's Recreation Association (WRA), 1946-1972 (formerly Women's Athletic Association W.A.A.) (Box 46)
    - Women's Residence Council, 1969-1971 (Box 46)
    - Woodrow Wilson Fellows, 1961-1970 (Box 46)
    - YM-YWCA Cabinet, 1967-1972 (Box 46)
    - YWCA, Young Women's Christian Association, 1947-1973 (Box 46)
    - YWCA, Asa Uoki (General Secretary Student Department, Japanese YWCA), 1963-1964 (Box 46)
    - Yearly Formal Opening of the Woman's College (see Flag Raising Ceremony, above) (Box 46)
    - 25th Anniversary, Woman's College, 1955 (Box 47)
    - Schedule of Course, 1947-1948; 1960 (Box 47)
  - Academic Dean,1936-1972[AcD30-60], 3 boxes
    1.5 ln. ft. (about 1,500 items) Arrangement: alphabetically
    These files contain subject folders concerning such areas as curriculum, faculty advisory system, academic standards committee, and transfers.
    - Academic Standards Committee, [FERPA] (Box 48)
    - Committee Organization at Duke, Committee on, [1954?] (Box 48)
    - Course Descriptions, n.d., 1948-1949; 1963 (Box 48)
    - Courses of Instruction, Committee on, 1948-1960 (Box 48)
    - Curriculum, 1951-1961 (Box 48)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1950-1960 (Box 48)
    - Departmental Majors, related work, 1948-1955 (Box 49)
    - Departmental Officers, 1950-1965 (Box 49)
    - English Department, 1951-1964 [FERPA] (Box 49)
    - Examination Schedules, 1948-1966 (Box 49)
    - Exchange Program - Free University Berlin, Germany, 1963-1965 (see also Study Abroad, Committee on, below; Exchange Program - Free University Berlin, Germany and Study Abroad, Committee on, in the Alphabetical Subject Files, above) (Box 49)
    - Faculty Advisors, 1959-1963 (Box 49)
    - Faculty Advisory System, 1954-1955 (see also the same title in the Alphabetical Subject Files, above) (Box 49)
    - Faculty Council, summary of actions, 1949-1960 (Box 49)
    - Honors, 1939-1960 (Box 49)
    - Majors List, 1966-1967 (Box 49)
    - Peace Corps, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Religion Department, 1966 (Box 49)
    - Study Abroad, Committee on, 1955-1966 (see also Exchange Program, above and Exchange Program - Free University Berlin, Germany and Study Abroad, Committee on, in the Alphabetical Subject Files, above) (Box 49)
    - Study Abroad, Committee on, 1955-1966, continued (Box 50)
    - Testing and Guidance, Bureau of, 1951-1960 (name changed to University Counseling Center, 1964; see also University Counseling Center in the Alphabetical Subject Files, above) (Box 50)
    - Transfer Credit, Correspondence, 1936-1952 (Box 50)
    - Who's Who in American Colleges and Universities, 1953-1963 (Box 50)
  - Assistant Dean of Women,1953-1973 [OAD59-72]., 4 boxes
    2.0 ln. ft. (about 2,000 items) Arrangement: alphabetically
    This collection consists of correspondence, memos, reports, and volumes from the office of Lillian Lee, Assistant Dean of Women. The material primary deals with housing: construction, room assignments, dormitory counselors, and dorm council budgets. The bulk of the material is from 1969-1971.
    - Academic Deans Meeting, 1967-1968 (see also the same title in the subseries Alphabetical Subject files, above) (Box 51)
    - Board of Visitors (see also "Women's Education in the 1970's below) (Box 51)
    - Foreign Student Scholarship Fund, 1956-1968 [FERPA] (Box 51)
    - House Counselors, In-service Training Program, 1959-1964, (see also House Counselor Study Group, 1957-1964 in the Alphabetical Subject Files, above) (Box 51)
    - House Counselors, Notes for, 1966 (see also House Counselor Study Group, 1957-1959 in the Alphabetical Subject Files, above) (Box 51)
    - House Counselors, Notes for, 1966-1970 (Box 51)
    - House Counselors, Notes for, continued (Box 52)
    - Housing, Central Campus, 1969-1970 (Box 52)
    - Housing, Experimental Dormitory, 1961-1967 [FERPA] (Box 52)
    - Housing, Experimental Dormitory, 1961-1967, continued [FERPA] (Box 52)
    - Housing, Experimental Dormitory Applications, 1966 [FERPA] (Box 52)
    - Housing, Thanksgiving and Christmas Recess, 1970-1971 (Box 52)
    - Housing, Townhouse Apartments, 1970 (Box 52)
    - Judicial Board, 1965 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-1973 (Box 52)
    - Pre-School Training Staff, 1959-1962 (Box 52)
    - Room Assignment, 1971-1972 (Box 52)
    - Secretary to the Assistant Dean, 1954-1968, book containing policies, form letters, etc. alphabetically indexed (Box 53)
    - Student Employment, 1953-1971 (Box 53)
    - Summer Session, 1971-1973 (Box 53)
    - Transfer Students, 1966; 1968; 1973 (Box 53)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1960-1961 (Box 53)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1961-1970, continued (Box 54)
    - "Women's Education in the 1970's," session of the Board of Visitors, 1966; 1971 (Box 54)
  - Reports to the Dean,1930-1971 [OD25-72]., 3 boxes
    1.5 ln. ft. (about 1,500 items) Arrangement: chronologically
    These files contain reports from the offices within the Woman's College to the Dean of the Woman's College so that her office could then prepare an annual report to the president of the University. Offices include Dean of Women, Religious life, Physical Education, the Infirmary, Dean of Instruction, Academic Dean, etc.
    - Reports to the Dean, 1930-1955 (Box 55)
    - Reports to the Dean, 1955-1966 (Box 56)
    - Reports to the Dean, 1966-1971 (Box 57)
  - Reports to the President, 1930-19723 [OD25-72]., 2 boxes
    1.0 ln. ft. (about 1,000 items) Arrangement: chronologically
    Dean of Woman's College annual report to the president of the University.
    - Reports to the President, 1930-1951 (Box 57)
    - Reports to the President, 1952-1972 (Box 58)
  - Staff Minutes, 1937-1971,[A82-90; OAD59-72; OD25-72; ODMGW33-69]., 4 boxes
    2.5 ln. ft. (about 2,500 items) Arrangement: chronologically
    - Minutes [FERPA], 1937-1960 (Box 59)
    - Minutes [FERPA], 1960-1966 (Box 60)
    - Minutes [FERPA], 1966-1969 (Box 61)
    - Agendas [FERPA], 1969-1971 (Box 62)
    - Minutes [FERPA], 1969-1970 (Box 62)
    - Agendas and minutes [FERPA], 1969-1970 (Box 62)
    - Minutes [FERPA], 1971 (Box 62)
  - Statistical Reports,1930-1960, [A83-38]., 1 boxes
    0.5 ln. ft. (about 500 items) Arrangement: chronologically
    General statistics gathered by the Woman's College including but limited to geographical distribution, religious affiliation, grade averages by class, house, and sorority, admissions, withdrawals, and the availability of dormitory space.
    - General Statistics, 1930-1960 (Box 63)
    - Study on Absences, 1957 (Box 63)
  - Scrapbooks and Student Organization's Activities, [Oversize], 1932-1969, 2 boxes
    6.0 ln. ft. (about 1,000 items) Arrangement: alphabetically
    Box 66 contains two unbound scrapbooks from Giles and Aycock Houses. These scrapbooks contain data sheets about the residents detailing such information as room, roommate, activities, jobs, hobbies, ambitions, offices, honors, and summer activities.
    - Class Business, 1965-1969 (Oversize-box 64)
    - Endowments, student gifts, 1932-1937 (Box 63)
    - Phi Kappa Delta, 1947-1963 (scrapbook) (Box 63)
    - Phi Kappa Delta, Initiations, Constitutions, and By-Laws, 1948-1960 (Box 63)
    - Phi Kappa Delta, President's Reports, 1950-1968 (Box 63)
    - Photo, Woman's College, undated (Box 63)
    - Sandals, history, 1932-1967 (scrapbook) (Box 63)
    - Sororities: Greek Booklet, 1967 (Box 63)
    - Terpsichorean' President, 1962-1965 (scrapbook) (Box 63)
    - Terpsichorean Club, 1958-1965 (scrapbook) (Box 63)
    - Aycock House, scrapbook, 1942-1948 (Oversize-box 65)
    - Giles House, scrapbook, 1942-1948 (Box 63)
    - Annual Treasurer's Reports of Woman's College Student Organizations, Bound volumes, 1936-1950 (Oversize-box 66)
    - Annual Treasurer's Reports of Woman's College Student Organizations, Bound volumes, 1950-1960 (Oversize-box 67)
- Audio-Visual
  - "Changing Image of Duke Women," 1965 Feb. (Box 63, Cd 1)